# **Rubiyat Hasan Siddik**

#### **Contact details:**

Contact no: +8801625571559

Mailing Address:

House: 22, Road-05, Shialbhari, Mirpur, Dhaka-1216 Email: <u>rubiyat21@gmail.com</u>, Skype: rubiyat.rumi

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/rubiyat-hasan-siddik-421612147



With my 3 years of IT experience in Software and Web Application Development. I have been developed various business application like – Garments ERP, Budgetary Control System, Agricultural Budget Management and transaction system, USI BD Control MIS, Content management system, Point of Sale, School Management System, Production Management application, Forum Discussion and many more.

Throughout my professional career, I have been developing business applications whether it is web based or desktop application including Web/Windows Services. I have been exercising Java and PHP platform for development. I am using Java SE, Java EE, Spring, Object Oriented PHP, Codelgniter, Laravel technologies for business layer development. For presentation layer I have been using HTML 5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JQuery/JavaScript, Ajax, vue.js, Angular.

I am a quick learner and with my knowledge, I want to make a sound position in software industry and work enthusiastically in team to achieve goal of the organization with devotion and hard work. I feel confident that I am the right person to help your company reach the next level of success.

## **Technical Profile Highlights**

## Language:

Java SE, Java EE, Spring Boot, PHP, Codelgniter, Laravel, Angular, vue.is, Ajax,

JQuery/JavaScript, Bootstrap, CSS3, HTML 5

#### **Database**

MySql, SQL Server

#### **Reporting Tools**

Jaspersoft, IReport

## **Employment History**

. A. Company: Intellier Limited
Position held: Developer

Period: 22 Dec 2019 - Present

## **Responsibilities:**

- Work under the supervision of a team lead.
- Carry out tasks assigned by team lead.
- Taking full responsibility of the assigned task.
- Work as a full stack java developer
- Restful API Development with spring boot and Integration API with Angular
- Developing Application Spring Boot for backend development and Angular, Nebular, Bootstrap for frontend development
- Practicing Agile Methodology.

B. Company: ATI Limited

Position held: Junior Programmer

# Period: 01 July 2018 - 30 November 2019

## Responsibilities:

- Work under the supervision of a team lead.
- · Carry out tasks assigned by team lead.
- Taking full responsibility of the assigned task.
- Solve any programmatically problem
- Play role as team leader for a USI BD Control MIS project
- Maintaining systems by monitoring, identifying and correcting software defects
- Work as a full stack PHP developer
- Developing Application Laravel, Codelgniter, PHP for backend development and vue.js, Ajax, JQuery/JavaScript, Bootstrap, CSS3, HTML 5 for frontend development
- Practicing Agile Methodology.

C. Company: Win-Win Service Provider Position held: Software Engineer

Period: 01 May 2018 - 30 June 2018

## **Responsibilities:**

- Work under the supervision of a team lead.
- Carry out tasks assigned by team lead.
- Taking full responsibility of the assigned task.

## **Educational History:**

#### **Graduation:**

# **Bachelor in Business Information Technology**

University of Greenwich, UK Session: 2018-2019

Diploma:

- International Advanced Diploma in Computer Studies National Computing Center, UK
- International Diploma in Computer Studies National Computing Center, UK
- International Foundation Year in Computer Studies National Computing Center, UK

#### **HSC (Higher School Certificate):**

# **Higher Secondary Certificate**

Dhaka Commerce College, Dhaka Board GPA 4.90 out of 5

Session: 2010-2011

# SSC (Secondary School Certificate):

#### **Secondary School Certificate**

Rupnagar Model School & College, Dhaka Board

GPA 4.94 out of 5 Session: 2008-2009

## **Certification Training and Course**

1. The Java Spring Tutorial: Learn Java's Popular Web Frame from Udemy

License Number: UC-LI8G6XFN

Certification URL: http://ude.my/UC-LI8G6XFN

2. Angular 5 (formerly Angular 2) - The Complete Guide from Udemy

License Number: UC-H2FHPXCZ

Certification URL: http://ude.my/UC-H2FHPXCZ

3. Advanced Javascript from Udemy

License Number: UC-63D54A8T

Certification URL: http://ude.my/UC-63D54A8T

4. PHP with Laravel for beginners - Become a Master in Laravel from Udemy

License Number: UC-6VATQ2UD

Certification URL: http://ude.my/UC-6VATQ2UD

5. Database Design and Management from Udemy

License Number: UC-MYELQNI6

Certification URL: http://ude.mv/UC-MYELQNI6

#### **Projects**

1. Garments ERP (Nidle): Nidle is an ERP solution for Garments industries which is integrated with different modules that cover all the aspects of your Garments Business. This solution supports multi-currency and multi-location based operations. It aims at keeping track of all the activities including receiving an order from buyer, quality check costing of order, resource planning, procurement of raw materials, production management, inventory management, import-export process, order reconciliation process etc.

Technology Use: Spring boot, Angular, Nebular, Bootstrap, MySql

2. **Budgetary Control System:** This application is developed for allocate company's all kind of budget, budget requisition, requisition disbursement and budget approval process. This application helps company planning, coordination between departments, decision-making, monitoring of operating results and motivation of personnel to achieve business objectives.

Technology Use: Spring boot, Angular, Nebular, Bootstrap, MySql

3. USI BD Control MIS: This project is web based management information system (MIS). The owner of this project is UNICEF. This application has multiple type of user and they can access the system as their role wise. It also maintain salt production, slat sale and salt sock. This application maintain all mill and their alt production, sale and stock. This application produce different kind of reports month or year wise.

Technology Use: Laravel, Javascript, Jquery, Ajax, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, MySql

4. Department of Agricultural Extension: This project is web based budget and transaction application. It is a Bangladesh government project. This application maintain fund which comes from different source. Then user can create budget from this fund. After that user allocate fund for all cost center. Cost center get fund and expense this fund by financial year wise. This application generate different kind of financial and general report for the authority.

Technology Use: Laravel, Javascript, Jquery, Ajax, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, MySql

## **Reference**

Zafar Iqbal, PhD	Shamsuddin Ahammad
Freelance Editor and Expert Reviewer	Sr. Software Engineer at About Time Technologies,
Ottawa, Ontario, Canada	L.L.C
ftri007@yahoo.com	s.ahammad@gmail.com
	Dhaka, Bangladesh